England, in the year 1215,
1215年 英格蘭
had been under the reign of King John for 16 years.
已被約翰王統治了16年
The most villainous of England's monarchs,
作為英格蘭最殘暴的君王
John was renowned for losing wars with France,
約翰王因對法戰爭的失利
levying punitive taxes,
苛捐重稅
and sleeping with the wives of barons.
以及與男爵妻子有染而臭名昭著
The barons finally rebelled against their king,
最終 男爵們開始反抗他們的國王
and became locked in a bloody civil war
發動了一場血腥的內戰
lasting for over three years and decimating both armies.
在長達三年的內戰中 雙方軍隊都傷亡慘重
In time, the Knights Templar were drawn into this conflict.
當時 聖殿騎士團也捲入了這場戰爭
With the help of these highly trained warrior monks,
在這些訓練有素的修道士的幫助下
King John and his royal army were eventually defeated.
男爵們最終打敗了約翰王和他的皇家軍隊
It was agreed that John could remain on the throne,
最終談判決定 約翰王可以繼續在位
on one condition...
但有一個條件...
that he would sign a document
他必須要簽署一份文件
upholding the rights and privileges of all free men,
不僅保證所有自由人民的各項權利
but ultimately limiting the power of the monarchy.
並從根本上抑制王權
Make it count.
君無戲言
The Magna Carta was sealed at Runnymede
1215年6月15日 在蘭尼米德
on the 15th of June in the year of our Lord 1215.
大憲章正式簽訂
It will be remembered throughout history.
這一時刻將會被歷史銘記
What is not remembered is what King John did next.
然而約翰王的後續舉動卻被人們淡忘
Sire?
陛下?
It's time.
時間到了
Hyah!
駕!
Hyah! Hyah!
駕! 駕!
England welcomes you.
英格蘭歡迎你
Does the Pope hold his word?
教皇是否會信守承諾?
Oh, how have faith, Captain Tiberius.
哦 要有信心 Tiberius隊長
His Eminence is waiting to hear you hold to yours.
他正期待得知你履行諾言
The Church will stay out of your lands, you have his word.
他向你保證 教會不會踏上你的領土
We'll get your country back.
我們會奪回你的國家
What say you?
所來何事?
Abbot Marcus. We seek shelter from the storm.
我是Marcus修道院長 希望能夠避雨
Open the gates!
打開城門!
Come and help.
快過來幫忙
What business do you have here?
你們有何貴幹?
Our business is with God at Canterbury.
我們要去坎特伯雷(英國國教的聖地)拜謁大主教
We need only shelter.
我們只想避雨
Shelter you shall have. Food also.
我們會為你提供住所 以及食物
You treat the Lord's servants well.
多謝您善待上帝的僕人
You wear the mark of the Templars, yet you carry no swords.
你們佩戴著聖殿騎士的標記 但沒有佩劍
These men have no more need to fight.
他們沒有必要再戰鬥了
Templars masking their faith and travelling without swords.
聖殿騎士標示信條 出行無須配劍
How noble!
好高尚!
As God is our witness, Baron, these men have nothing to hide.
上帝為證 男爵 這些人無需隱藏
Abbot, save your benedictions. The Templars fought against the King.
院長 別說好話了 聖殿騎士對抗國王
Now you sleep in a king's castle. These men have plenty to hide.
如今你們住在國王的城堡裡 他們要隱藏的東西多了
You there. What say you?
你啊 你在做什麼?
They say nothing. They hold vows of silence.
他們不說話 他們在履行沉默的誓言
Templars without tongues. Very well.
不會說話的聖殿騎士 很好
Just be gone by the morning.
明早就離開吧
Back inside!
進去!
Marshal.
Marshal啊
When I accept guardianship over men who take the vows of silence,
我接受監護髮誓沉默的人任務之時
I'm also informed of what led them to me in the first place.
我也知道了為何最初選中了我
I know the Templars placed a heavy burden on you.
我知道聖殿騎團士讓你身負重擔
I know you're deeply scarred.
我知道你傷痕纍纍
The cross on your tunic
你外衣上的十字架
is a symbol of your faith in God's will.
象徵你信仰上帝
It should not be full of the torment, it now bears upon your soul.
它不應帶來痛苦 但現在卻折磨著你的靈魂
When we arrive at Canterbury,
等我們到達坎特伯雷
I'm requesting your leave from the Order of the Knights Templar.
我會要求你離開聖殿騎士團
Garrison men!
守軍!
King John!
約翰王!
Men, to the gates! It's the King!
來人 打開城門! 是國王!
Open the gates for the King!
為國王打開城門!
Marshal, did you see royal colours?
Marshal 你看到皇家旗幟了嗎?
Is that your hand, Darnay?
Darnay 這是你的筆跡嗎?
Forced, Your Highness.
我是被逼的 陛下
The barons threatened my life, forcing me to sign it and betray you.
男爵們以性命相要挾 強迫我簽名背叛您
I know the feeling.
我深有體會
Hang him!
絞刑!
This insanity must cease.
必須阻止這瘋狂的行徑
Open the door. His quarrel is not with us.
開門 他和我們並無冤仇
If you three stand before the King, there will be nothing but death.
如果你們三個出現在國王面前 那就只有死路一條
What good fortune, Darnay. It seems you will have your last rites.
真幸運啊 Darnay 看來你可以做臨終祈禱了
My Lord, Templars.
陛下 聖殿騎士
He's travelling en route to Canterbury with Templars.
他和聖殿騎士一起 準備去往坎特伯雷
To what do I owe the pleasure of the Church visiting my castle?
我有何榮幸 能讓教會的人造訪我的城堡?
We were in the storm, Sire. Baron Darnay granted us your hospitality.
陛下 我們遇到了暴雨 Darnay男爵展示了您的仁慈關愛
- We?  - My fellow priests.
- 我們?  - 與我同行的神父
Ah, yes, I heard.
啊 是 我聽到的
Templars.
聖殿騎士
Sire, we entered your castle as unarmed men. We seek no fight.
陛下 我們進城時未帶任何武器 我們不想引起爭端
Are you aware, Abbot,
修道院長 你有沒有意識到
that your kind stood at Runnymede and forced my signature,
是你們這群人在蘭尼米德 強迫我簽字
and now you sleep under my roof?
而如今你卻休憩在我的屋檐之下
Your Highness, we travel to Canterbury
陛下 我們遵守教規
with simple articles of faith.
前往坎特伯雷
I ask your mercy that we may pass.
請您恩准我們通行
And I will grant you the same mercy
我賜予你的仁慈
that the Church and the barons of this country bestowed unto me.
與教會和男爵們給予我的一樣
"Do unto others", isn't that right, Abbot?
"己所不欲 勿施於人" 不是嗎 修道院長?
Tiberius!
來人 Tiberius!
Don't let them go!
別放走他們!
Ride!
快走!
There is worth...
每個人...
in every death.
都會死得其所
And I will see it now in yours.
我必將看到你離去的意義
- You saw the King?  - Yes. And he saw me.
- 你親眼看到了國王?  - 是的 而且他也看到我了
I didn't imagine that even he was capable of such cruelty.
我不敢想像他竟然如此殘暴
Abbot Marcus was the finest of men.
Marcus院長是我見過最好的人
Tell me, why did he request that you leave the Order?
告訴我 他為什麼要求你脫離聖殿騎士團?
- Your Grace, I did not wish to be dismissed.  - But that's not what I asked.
- 主教大人 我不想離職  - 這不是我的問題
You were in the Holy Lands?
你曾經到過耶路撒冷?
Hm. Some men have returned from defending our faith
嗯 有些人為捍衛信仰而去
only to find themselves questioning it.
回來卻發現自己對此產生了質疑
Now you must ask yourself, Thomas...
Thomas 你必須捫心自問...
what is in your heart?
你心裡有的是什麼?
Rebellion or revenge.
反抗還是復仇
I suppose it makes no difference as the King has the devil in his.
有個內心邪惡的國王 我想這兩者沒什麼區別了
I don't care if he's talking to the Pope! I have to see him now!
就算他在和教皇談話我也不管! 我現在就要見他!
And as we speak of the devil...
說到邪惡...
My Lord Archbishop.
尊敬的大主教大人
They told me about Darnay.
他們和我說了Darnay的事
We took John at his word...
我們相信了約翰的話...
and now he raises a bitch's army with God's teeth.
如今他以上帝之名集結了一隊狗娘養的軍隊
I'll bow to no king with piss for blood!
我不向這種豬狗不如的國王屈膝!
Baron William de Albany, Brother Thomas Marshal.
William de Albany男爵 這是Thomas Marshal兄弟
Brother Thomas comes directly from Darnay Castle.
Thomas兄弟由Darnay城堡而來
You must forgive our Baron, Brother Thomas,
請原諒男爵 Thomas兄弟
his tongue is not always so profane.
男爵說話很少如此粗俗
Now, you should know that Rome sides with the King.
如今 你們應該知道羅馬教廷站在國王那邊
And the Pope would bless what the King did to Abbot Marcus?
教皇為國王對Marcus院長所做的一切祈福?
More or less.
差不多
I am to be excommunicated for writing Magna Carta .
我因撰寫了大憲章 將被開除教籍
- How long have we got?  - God knows.
- 我們還有多少時間?  - 天知道
Your Grace, this...
主教大人 必須...
king... must be stopped.
有人... 阻止國王
I cannot, in all honesty, ask you to fight, Thomas,
老實說 我不能要求你去戰鬥 Thomas
but if you choose to take up your sword, you have my blessing.
但是如果你要拿起武器 我會為你祈禱
It's a good omen.
這是個好兆頭
God is with us.
上帝與我們同在
Prince Louis has an army may be persuaded to join us.
也許我們能說服路易王子(法國國王路易八世)發兵支援我們
Asking the French for help...
向法國人求助...
that's cursing the blind for the wicked.
那就好像是病急亂投醫
If John takes the Dover Road to London
如果約翰取道多佛爾大道前往倫敦的話
he has to cross the Medway here at Rochester.
他就必須要穿過梅德韋河 到達羅徹斯特城堡
I'll seize Rochester Castle.
我會先佔領羅徹斯特城堡
Delay them. That'll give you time to negotiate with the French.
拖住他們 這樣您就有時間與法國人談判了
We have no force to fight the King.
我們沒有軍隊對抗國王
I have a few men I can count on.
我有幾個可以信賴的人
Absolutely not. Suicide is a sin in the eyes of the Church, Baron.
絕對不行 男爵 在教會看來 自殺是一種罪過
Your Grace, I'm afraid I only see one thing.
主教大人 我發現了一件事
From Rochester, the King is able to dispatch his troops and supplies
國王能夠從羅徹斯特城堡向全國派兵遣將
all over the country.
補給物資
It is his keystone. Without it we will not stop him.
這是他的基石 失去此地 將無法阻止他
All my sins to this.
我所有的罪孽都源於此
May God protect what we are about to do.
願上帝保佑我們的行動
Guy!
Guy啊!
Squire!
護衛!
I want you to ride back.
我要你回去
No. I know how to fight.
不 我知道如何戰鬥
You see how he talks to me?
你看到他怎麼和我說話嗎?
Have you ever killed a man, Squire? Eh?
你殺過人嗎 護衛? 嗯?
Then you will learn, it is not a noble thing.
到時候你就知道 這絕對不是件高尚的事情
Not even when it's for freedom?
即使是為自由而戰?
Not even when it is for God.
即使是為上帝而戰
Hah!
駕!
Look at you!
看看你!
Any one of you throws a turd or a bean, I'll get you!
不論是誰向我扔狗屎或者豆子 我都不會放過你!
And you know I will!
你們知道我會的!
- Where's the butchers?  - Over there.
- 屠夫在哪裡?  - 那裡
I'll remember your faces!
我會記住你的樣子!
Sheep shears! They're sharp! Sharp sheep shears!
羊毛剪! 夠鋒利啊! 鋒利的羊毛剪!
- I'm looking for Daniel Marks.  - Wait here.
- 我找Daniel Marks  - 在這裡等著
Marks!
Marks啊!
Whatever it is or how much...
不管什麼事 不管多少錢...
- just get me out of here, Baron.  - Done. Where's de Lacy?
- 只要能讓我離開這裡 男爵  - 行 Lacy在哪裡?
- He went back to Poitou  - Becket?
- 他回到Poitou了  - Becket呢?
You don't want him.
你不會想帶上他的
Templars. They've come back.
聖殿騎士 他們回來了
Here. You may need protection.
拿著 你需要東西防身
Get up.
起來
I said, get up!
我說了 起來!
You sack of shit!
你個賤人!
Billy.
Billy啊
What told me I'd see you?
你找我什麼事?
What's with the altar boy?
這個教會的人怎麼也在?
Billy all tied up with God again?
Billy又要為信仰而戰了?
- This is not our man.  - Hoy!
- 他不是我們需要的人  - 呵!
I'm his man, don't you worry about that.
我是他的人 你不需要擔心
If he pays me enough, I'll split the gut of any man alive.
只要他給的夠多 我願意活扒了所有人
Ain't that right, Billy boy?
沒說錯吧 Billy?
- Who's with you?  - Gil Becket. Daniel Marks.
- 你還找了誰?  - Gil Becket和Daniel Marks
The last time we were all together must have been Dieppe.
上次我們聚首還是在迪耶普(法國城市)
The days when the King was still good to us.
那時候國王待我們還很好
He's taken all the castles along the coast.
他已經佔領了沿岸的所有城堡
If he takes Rochester, he'll control southern England.
如果再佔領羅徹斯特城堡 他就能控制整個英格蘭南部
If the whispers I've heard are true, he's too strong now.
如果我聽到的消息是真的 他現在太強大了
He's got an army of Danish mercenaries.
他有一支丹麥傭軍
Wait for him in London.
在倫敦等著他吧
Do you think I want this? I'm not a soldier, not any more.
你以為我想這樣嗎? 我不再是個戰士了
I'm a fat wool merchant with a hen-pecking wife and three daughters.
我只是個發福的羊毛商人 有個碎嘴的妻子和三個女兒
But, unfortunately, he won't let it be.
但是 不幸的是 國王他不願這樣
I'm sorry, Baron. Not this one.
對不起 男爵 這次不行
I learnt about the Crusades.
我知道十字軍的事
Is it true what the Templar swords say?
聖殿騎士的劍上寫的是真的嗎?
"Blessed and omnipotent is the warrior of Christ" ?
"基督的戰士是被祝福的 他們無所不能"?
Yeah, water. Water.
好的 水 給我水
- Hey!  - Agh!
- 嘿!  - 啊!
What do you think he's worth?
你覺得他哪裡值得了?
- Are you sorry for what you've done?  - Bollocks.
- 對你的所作所為感到內疚嗎?  - 胡說
- Release him.  - Amen!
- 放了他  - 阿門!
Papa!
爸爸!
Get inside. Now!
回屋子裡去 快!
- Joseph.  - Baron.
- 好 Joseph  - 男爵
- Daniel.  - Wulfstan.
- Daniel  - 你好 Wulfstan
Becket.
Becket 你好
You... are a filthy whore, Becket.
你... 是個下流的賤人 Becket
So was she.
她也是
We'll never hold that castle with this lot.
就我們這些人守不住城堡的
They may not be worthy of that cross you wear,
他們也許配不上你佩戴的十字架
but they'll hold the castle.
但是他們能守住城堡
Not for England... not for God...
不為英格蘭... 不為上帝...
but for me.
而是為了我
Winter's soon, so if I'm not back by first snowfall,
冬天快來了 如果下第一場雪的時候 我還沒有回來
take your sister to your aunt, give her this.
帶著你的妹妹去找你姑姑 把這個給她
Work hard.
努力幹活
Be polite.
要有禮貌
And what's written here is true?
這上面寫的是真的?
From my ears to this paper, Sire.
我親耳所聞 陛下
Tiberius, six of your fastest scouts to Rochester.
Tiberius 派6名最快的偵察兵到羅徹斯特城堡
Instruct them to hold the castle.
告訴他們 守住城堡
- Kill anyone they find there.  - Hyah!
- 殺掉找到的所有人  - 駕!
Money.
錢
How do you know these men?
你怎麼認識他們?
So what does that make you?
你為什麼那麼做?
Worthless.
沒用的傢伙
There it is.
就是那裡
Looks small from here.
從這看真小
That... small castle...
那座... 小小的城堡...
controls all the land as far as you can see.
控制著你目光所及的這片土地
Be patient, Squire.
耐心點 護衛
As long as there's women.
只要那裡有女人
- What say you?  - I bring business from Archbishop Langton.
- 所來何事?  - 蘭頓大主教派我來的
Isabel!
喂Isabel!
We have company.
有客人在
I have told you before, I will not tolerate drinking.
我告訴過你 我不能容忍你喝酒
You won't tolerate anything.
你什麼都不能容忍
My lord. We have men at the gate.
大人 有人想進城
I tolerate the politics of the King, Isabel.
我容忍國王的政見 Isabel
Our marriage was arranged for land and wealth.
我們的婚姻是為了土地和財富
It would be well if you were to remember that.
只要你謹記這點 就萬事大吉了
And he owns us, body and soul.
他擁有我們 身體和靈魂
Open the gates! Let them in!
打開大門! 讓他們進來!
You arrive unexpected, Baron de Albany.
Albany男爵 你不期而至
What matter does His Grace send this late?
大主教因何事派你們而來?
That we claim this castle in the name of the rebellion.
以反抗軍的名義接管這座城堡
If your visit is to claim my castle, Baron...
如果你是為了佔有我城堡而來 男爵...
you're too late.
太遲了
Unusual saddles.
少見的馬鞍
- Danish.  - What was that?
- 丹麥人  - 什麼意思?
They're Danish. They arrived last night.
是丹麥人的 他們昨晚到的
The King's scouts. His army is less than a day away.
這是國王的偵察兵 大軍還有不到一天就到了
Oaks, get the guard here quickly.
Oaks 快叫衛兵過來
That one was at Darnay Castle two days ago.
那傢伙兩天前在Darnay城堡
No, no, no!
不 不 不!
Marshal, down!
Marshal 趴下!
Baron.
男爵
Stand down! Stand down!
住手! 住手!
Listen to me.
聽我說
By the archbishop, we claim this castle in the name of the rebellion.
奉大主教之令 我們以反抗之名佔領這座城堡
The rebellion's over. The King surrendered to the great charter.
反抗已經結束了 國王已簽署大憲章
Magna Carta.
大憲章
This one sealed by the King's own hand.
這是國王親自簽署的
And now... he's executing everybody who supported it.
現在... 他卻要處死支持這份憲章的人
But does the Pope know that the Archbishop is claiming royal castles, against the King?
但教皇知道大主教要佔領這座城堡 背叛國王嗎?
I watched as three of my brothers were killed
我親眼見到三位兄弟
by the soft hand of a king
被國王殺害
that is murdering his way across the country.
他正在國內掀起一場大屠殺
And he does so with the Pope's blessing.
教皇卻祝福他的所作所為
The French army make sail any day now.
法國軍隊隨時都會起航
Giving us... a new king.
選出... 一位新國王
A true king.
一位真正的國王
Seal the gates.
關上城門
Lock all the doors! Move! And, Oaks, no one else comes in.
關上所有的門! 去! 還有 Oaks 任何人不准進來
Very well.
很好
Well, Marshal...
呃 Marshal...
you got us our castle.
你幫我們拿下了城堡
- What is your strength, Captain?  - Eleven men-at-arms.
- 你有多少人 隊長?  - 十一個全副武裝的壯漢
- We have less than 20 men?  - And these walls.
- 我們只有不到20人?  - 還有這些城牆
- They've never been breached.  - Does the keep have a portcullis?
- 它們從未被攻破  - 塔樓裡有升降閘門嗎?
- It does.  - Good.
- 有  - 好的
- Once it's down, no one gets in.  - Water. Where is the supply?
- 放下它 沒人能進來  - 還有水 水源在哪?
From the well. Draws straight from the river. No one here gets thirsty.
從水井裡 直接從河裡引來的 供給充足
- It's good, it's not sick or brackish?  - Water's good, sir.
- 很好 水源是乾淨 沒有異味的吧?  - 水很好 先生
Guy, with me.
Guy 跟我來
These walls are designed to be defended by one man per station.
這些城牆都是一人一崗式設計
Outlook is perfect. Any approach can be seen for miles.
視野極佳 幾英里外有敵來襲都可以看到
Now, let's see the gatehouse.
現在 去看看門樓
You, day or night, stay alert. Now open it up.
你 24小時保持警惕 現在開門
What's the problem?
有什麼問題嗎?
There's no moat.
沒有壕溝
That'll do.
可以了
Now, when they come...
現在 敵人來襲...
hit them hard.
用力出擊
Hit the post.
砍木樁
I said, hit the post. Hard.
我說了 砍這木樁 用力
They'll come? The French.
他們會來嗎? 法國人
We waited for the French at Damascus. They didn't come then.
我們在大馬士革(當時埃及首都)期待過法國人 他們沒來
Even to a Frenchman I think Rochester is nearer than Damascus.
我想對法國人來說 羅徹斯特要比大馬士革近
Hit it.
砍吧
You better hit it harder than that, boy.
孩子 你得砍得比我那下還狠
Or you'll be dead before they get here.
不然在法國人來之前你就掛了
They hate women.
他們討厭女人
Just to look at one's a sin.
把女人當成一種罪惡
Some people say they worship the devil.
有人說他們崇拜魔鬼
Celibates with stone hearts.
鐵石心腸 孤獨終身
Then I have a stone heart, too, Maddy.
那我也是鐵石心腸了 Maddy
I didn't mean it like that.
我不是那個意思
A Templar offers his chastity to God,
聖殿騎士把忠貞奉獻給上帝
but a wife...
但妻子...
she suffers hers by her husband.
要把自己的忠貞奉獻給丈夫
My husband's appetites don't include me.
我丈夫對我沒有慾望
Thank the Lord Mary herself.
多謝聖母
Now, I am... curious, Albany.
Albany 現在 我... 很好奇
Why is it that you and your friends are so struck with this rebellion?
為什麼你和你朋友們如此堅定地要反抗?
- Mm.  - Because we are for the people.
- 唔  - 因為我們是為了人民
I see your esquire is well-trained in the art of naivety.
我看你表現得十分天真嘛
- Go on.  - Call me naive if you will, sir,
- 繼續  - 請儘管說我天真吧 先生
but the people deserve more than a king that treats them like animals.
但人民的國王 不應當是一個把他們當做牲畜的人
Ah, bold words for a Squire.
噢 一個護衛的無畏之言
Have you read Magna Carta?
你讀過大憲章嗎?
- I...  - Ah, I see. You can't read Latin.
- 我...  - 嗷 我知道了 你不懂拉丁文
It's a pity, arguing from ignorance.
真遺憾 無知的陳述
Argumentum ad ignorantiam, ab uno disce omnes.
人以群分
That's Roman, isn't it?
那是羅馬話吧?
Excuse my wife's bold tongue.
請原諒我妻子的冒失
Becket, I'm gonna need you on the far wall.
Becket 到最遠的城牆去
- Guy can't defend it on his own.  - Do it yourself.
- Guy一個人守不住的  - 要去自己去
What?
什麼?
You want a drink? A woman?
想喝酒? 還是想要女人?
Don't you sniff your nose at me?
不要總盛氣凌人
I've been places. I've seen what your holy brothers have done.
我到過許多地方 見識過你聖潔的兄弟們做過什麼
Your pious bile makes me sick.
你那虛偽的勇敢讓我想吐
Becket. I want you outside.
Becket 出來
I'll watch your boy's back, but who's watching mine?
我會照顧你的小兄弟 但誰會照顧我的?
To the battlements!
上城垛!
- To the battlements!  - Right away!
- 上城垛!  - 馬上!
- Take your positions, men!  - Get those men up here, quickly!
- 堅守崗位 夥計!  - 讓那些人上來 快點!
Mercel, they're here!
Mercel 他們來了!
Let's see what rats have taken up in my home.
我們看看那些叛徒都在我家做了些什麼
Move it! Come on!
移開它! 來!
Albany, a word. You cannot engage the King without considering terms.
Albany 我有話要說 你不能毫無理由就與國王交戰
He wants our heads on spikes. Where are the terms in that?
他想殺了我們 這又有什麼理由?
There are some in here who didn't pick this fight.
有人不想參加戰鬥
Ask yourself who you're for, Cornhill.
Cornhill 捫心自問 你要站在哪邊
The King or the country? Because we both can't be wrong.
是國王還是國家? 我們都不能出錯
They're here.
他們來了
Albany!
Albany 出來!
How did he know? What can we do for you, John?
他怎麼知道我在這? 我們能為你做些什麼 約翰?
Baron William de Albany.
William de Albany男爵
The Pope has ordered me to reclaim my country.
我奉教皇之命收回我的國家
Now, surely you don't bar your door against a king, and the church?
現在 你肯定不會把國王和教會拒之門外吧?
Does he know you sealed a charter...
他知道你簽署了憲章...
giving the people of England freedom,
予英格蘭人民以自由
and that now you go back on your word?
但是又想言而無信嗎?
England is mine, Albany.
Albany 英格蘭是我的
God's will bestowed it unto me, the Pope blesses it to me,
上帝將它賜予我 教皇為它祈福
and this castle belongs to me!
這城堡屬於我!
You're no more a king...
你不是國王...
than the boil on my arse!
你臭名昭著!
What a tedious little man.
惹人厭的個小人
Get the swords now. Come on!
馬上去拿劍 快!
Stay by your posts.
堅守崗位
Remember, they have to climb over these walls.
記住 他們要翻過城牆
And we do not.
但我們不用
So you stand firm!
所以守住!
Have you ever fought so many with so few?
你像這樣以少敵多過嗎?
Uh... huh. Don't you forget, you hold the wall, huh?
呃... 呼 別忘了 守住城牆 知道嗎?
Now, go to your post.
現在 去你的崗位
North and south advance!
南北挺進!
Get ready, archers!
射手準備!
Loose!
放!
Take cover!
尋找掩護!
And again! Take cover!
再來! 尋找掩護!
Get down!
趴下!
Ha-ha!
哈哈!
Come on, lads, come on! Take your positions! Look lively!
快 小伙子 快! 堅守崗位! 打起精神來!
Take cover, lads! Take cover!
尋找掩護 小伙子! 尋找掩護!
Again!
再來!
Albany!
Albany注意!
Archers! They're coming!
射手! 他們來了!
Make a stand! Ready?
就位! 準備
Load arrows!
拉弓!
Loose!
放!
- Oil! Bring up that oil!  - Ready!
- 油! 把油拿上來!  - 預備!
- Oil!  - Watch your back!
- 油!  - 小心後面!
Take cover!
躲起來!
Becket!
Becket啊!
Come on. This way.
來 這邊
- What do we do?  - Pray God is with them.
- 我們要做什麼?  - 祈禱上帝保佑他們
Becket!
Becket啊!
Guy!
Guy 小心!
Show that to your mother!
給你媽看吧!
Now, get up!
現在 起來!
I said get up!
我說站起來!
Now, you hit him. Hard!
現在 去砍他 用力!
Behind you! Clear!
我在你們後面! 讓開!
Take cover!
躲起來!
They're running!
他們跑了!
- They're retreating!  - They've had enough, Baron.
- 他們撤退了  - 他們傷亡慘重 男爵
Bastards! Go on, run!
雜種! 繼續 快跑!
Come on, you foreign whores!
來啊 你們這些賤人!
You fought bravely.
你戰鬥英勇
You did not see everything.
有些事你並不知道
There's no finding peace after knowing this.
明白這點後 我覺得不會有和平的一天
Faith, Guy.
信念 Guy
Only the weak believe that what they do in battle...
只有弱者才會認為自己在戰鬥中的表現...
is who they are as men.
體現出了男子漢氣概
Put him with the others.
和其他人放在一起
Pack them over there. Over there, that's it.
把他們放那 那 就那
Baron Albany...
Albany男爵...
in less than a day...
一天不到...
you have stripped away everything I gave the people in this castle.
你就奪去了 我給予城堡裡的人們的一切
- Get off my back.  - You were hellbent on this fight!
- 走開  - 你在戰鬥中不顧一切!
You made us all hostages to your cause, not the rebellion's.
我們變成了你自己的人質 而不是反抗軍的人質
And this was not just another castle!
這不僅僅是一個城堡!
This was my home!
這是我家!
Now clear your mess up.
給我打掃乾淨
Shut the door.
關門
Still now.
冷靜下來
Wait. Here.
等等 過來
- This man is bleeding.  - On the table.
- 他在流血  - 躺到桌上
No. Wait. This will stop the flow.
不 等等 這樣可以止血
I'm gonna pull this hard.
我會把這個拉緊
The bone's not broken, but...
沒有骨折 不過...
Go on, do it, do it.
繼續 來吧 來吧
Keep it clean, and watch him close.
保持清潔 好好照顧他
Templar.
聖殿騎士
- Your neck.  - No.
- 你的脖子  - 沒事
Sit.
坐下
Please.
請
If the bleeding doesn't stop, shall I fasten a belt around your neck?
如果止不住血 我要不要給你脖子系根帶子?
My maid tells me you cannot look at women.
我的侍女告訴我 你不能看女人
What is your name?
你叫什麼?
Am I to assume your silence means you cannot talk to women either?
是不是可以認為 你沉默是因為你也不能和女人說話?
My name is Thomas Marshal.
我叫Thomas Marshal
There it is.
好了
And were many sacred vows broken by that revelation?
這次反叛是不是打破了很多神聖誓言?
It's not like the others. The river naturally defends.
這裡和其他地方不同 河流是天然的防禦屏障
Walls built... so a few can stop many.
高築的城牆... 所以他們寡能敵眾
Don't insult me, Captain.
別耍我了 隊長
I know the qualities of a Norman keep.
我很瞭解諾曼要塞的情況
What I am having trouble with...
我不瞭解的是...
is how a thousand men could have failed so miserably against twenty.
我們千人的隊伍怎麼會被20人打得潰不成軍
Those men fight hard. For what?
那些人拼了命地抵抗 為了什麼?
A small rock in a field?
就為了荒野中這座小城堡?
We go around.
我們出去走走
My great, great grandfather built that rock
我的曾曾祖父在攻克這個國家後
when he conquered this country.
築造了這座城堡
Strategically, it fortifies London and controls all of southern England.
它賦有戰略意義 加強了倫敦的防禦能力 並控制了英國的南部
Why in God's name do you think they chose to hole up there in the first place?
否則你以為 他們為什麼一開始就選擇了躲在那兒?
What will please your people more, Captain?
什麼更能取悅你的部下 隊長?
That your men died in a great battle,
是你的士兵在一場偉大戰役中犧牲
or that your reward for helping me is the Church leaving your lands alone?
還是幫助我取得勝利後 教會允許讓你的領地獨立?
For that is what the Pope promised he would do.
那就是教皇承諾的條件
Now, however small it may seem...
雖然那座城堡看起來...
with that rock, the rest of this country follows.
很渺小 但它是決定這個國家命運的關鍵
Now you see what he means to do.
現在他想做什麼 你們都看到了
I say this to each of you.
大家都聽好了
There's a night out there...
外面夜正深...
deep enough for a man to slip away, if he should wish.
誰想逃跑 都完全可以趁著夜色離開
And I would understand.
我能理解
I think you upset him.
你嚇到他了
What about you, Marks?
你呢 Marks?
I walked into this outside Toulouse.
這是在圖盧茲外受的傷
Both times we saw it through. What do you think I'm doing here?
那兩次我們都熬過來了 你以為我來這兒做什麼的?
I don't take a man's money and run.
我不會拿了人家的錢就跑的
Mr Phipps, are you and your garrison men still for the fight?
Phipps先生 您和您的駐軍還會繼續戰鬥嗎?
All six of us. Good and ready, sir.
我們六人隨時整裝待發 閣下
I saw you with the Templar.
我看見你和那個聖殿騎士了
I think he has a mind for you.
我覺得他對你有意思
His mind possesses nothing I care to think about.
我沒興趣瞭解他對什麼有意思
There is something not normal with him. It's his manner.
他有點不尋常 我是說他的禮儀方面
He looks but won't talk.
他看著人的時候就不會說話
Then he talks and nothing he says settles with me.
一說話就沒有迴旋的餘地
Don't tell me that was his way before he became a Templar. I wouldn't believe it.
他在成為聖殿騎士前絕不是這樣的 肯定不會是這樣的
- My Lady.  - What?
- 夫人  - 怎麼了?
That's a great deal of thinking...
對一個您沒什麼興趣的人...
for someone you don't want to think about.
您想得其實很多了
They're building something.
他們在建什麼東西
What do you think it is?
你覺得是什麼?
Your royal engineer, Sire.
您的御用工程師 陛下
- Will it work?  - There's no moat, er... So, er...
- 這能行嗎?  - 沒有護城河 呃... 所以 呃...
There's no moat and no excuses. Finish it.
沒有護城河就別找借口了 快點完工
I am sorry for what I said to you.
很抱歉我對你說了那些話
I was wrong.
我錯了
What happens next... to us?
接下來 我們... 會發生什麼?
- All of us?  - They will attack again.
- 我們所有人?  - 他們會再度發起攻擊
And we will hold again.
而我們能再次守住
The French...
法國那邊...
made sail with an army to stand by us.
已經有一支軍隊起航來支援我們了
You really believe they will come?
你真的相信他們會來?
Hm.
嗯
Thou shall not lie, Thomas.
你不該說謊的 Thomas
Certainly not for the French.
法國人肯定不會來的
Definitely not to me. It isn't worth it.
我覺得肯定不會的 不值得
Does that break Templar laws?
那樣是否違背了聖殿騎士的規定?
Mm.
嗯
Some would say yes.
有人會說是的
Put the sword down.
把劍放下
If they do come, I will need to know how to use this.
如果他們真的來了 我得學會如何用劍
- Is this how you hold it?  - If you want your opponent to win.
- 你們是這樣拿劍的?  - 如果你想讓敵人贏的話
I fight...
我會戰鬥到底的...
so you don't have to.
所以你不必學會使劍
Siege tower.
是攻城塔樓
Making quick work of it. Damn it.
建得還挺快 該死
Baron, I have an idea.
男爵 我有個主意
What happens if this doesn't work?
這辦法沒用的話 怎麼辦?
- Don't ask.  - What could be worse than this?
- 別問了  - 還有什麼能比這更糟的?
Squire, would you ever kill a woman?
護衛 你會殺女人嗎?
- Never.  - Not even if it meant saving her life?
- 絕不  - 即使是為了救她?
That's it, heave it down.
就那樣 斜下來
Holy Saint Joseph! Look who it is.
天堂聖徒約翰! 看看這是誰
His Majesty is ready, My Lord.
主啊 陛下準備就緒
- Prince Louis holds in France.  - They haven't sailed yet?
- Louis王子被困在法國了  - 他們還沒起航?
- He's buying time to negotiate terms.  - Negotiate terms!
- 他在爭取時間談判  - 談判!
The King enslaves this country,
國王奴役了整個國家
the Pope defends him and calls the Magna Carta heresy,
教皇還擁護他 判定大憲章違背教義
and France uses this tyranny for a better deal?
而法國還想從這暴政中獲利?
- Are there any men willing to fight?  - A few.
- 有人願意參與反叛嗎?  - 不多
Many thought the rebellion was over because John signed the Magna Carta.
很多人認為叛亂已經結束了 因為約翰王已經簽署了大憲章
In some ways, it was the smartest thing he did.
從某些方面來說 這是他做過最明智的事
Well, all that is done.
事已至此
Let Rome pronounce whatever holy dictum it pleases.
羅馬那邊樂意宣佈什麼神聖聲明 都隨他們去吧
They won't tell me that God is their possession.
反正他們也不能說 上帝歸他們所有
I leave for France at once. You gather what men you can.
我立刻去法國 你們盡可能招兵買馬
And prepare London for war.
準備好倫敦一戰
And Rochester?
那羅徹斯特城堡呢?
- Baron Albany?  - Pray God is with them.
- Baron男爵嗎?  - 願上帝與他們同在
Take cover!
尋找掩護!
Excellent. Excellent.
很好 很好
Go on. Faster!
繼續 快點!
Lock it!
固定住!
- Lock!  - And fire!
- 固定!  - 發射!
They have built an engine?
他們建了個發射器?
Take cover!
尋找掩護!
All of you, outside.
所有人 出去
Wulfstan, you've broken through!
Wulfstan 你亂了他們的陣腳!
Now, come on! Give them hellfire!
來吧! 給他們來一炮!
Heave! Heave!
拉呀! 拉呀!
Lock it! Fire pot, Guy!
固定! 火罐 Guy!
You heathen dogs!
你們這群野狗!
Bring it a bit forward!
往前來點!
Light it! Light it!
點燃它! 點燃它!
Loose!
發射!
Goddamn devils! Murdering goddamn whores!
該死的混蛋! 把那群婊子養的給我宰了!
Yes! They burn!
中了! 燒起來了!
Do not record that!
不許記下來!
Bitches!
混蛋!
This bastard king, Wulfstan.
那個暴君 Wulfstan
Aye.
是啊
After that, the king did not come again.
那之後 國王沒有再來了
But the rains did.
然而雨來了
And the days grew short as autumn turned to winter.
秋去冬來 白晝越來越短
They were too cold to fight, and too hungry.
人們又餓又冷 無法應戰
The castle stores were empty...
城堡內的存糧也空了...
and they had taken to eating the horses.
他們開始吃馬匹
Save for one.
只剩下了一匹
Marshal's.
是Marshal的
But a Templar is forbidden to eat his horse.
但聖殿騎士不能吃自己的戰馬
Their order dictates that it must die in battle.
他們的規定是 戰馬只能死於戰場上
So 13 hungry souls and one horse would remain.
所以剩下了13個飢腸轆轆的人和一匹馬
Still they waited.
他們仍在等待
And so too did the King.
國王也是如此
They could smell his food, hear his army's song.
他們可以聞到他食物的味道 聽見他軍隊的歌聲
For attrition is one man's ally and another man's curse.
耗損的是一方的齊心協力和另一方的詛咒連連
So they became cursed men.
所以他們成了被詛咒的人
And as weeks turned to months,
時光飛逝
their minds took to places they should not...
他們的思想開始變得消極...
where a man sees only doubt and has no worth at all.
對一切只剩懷疑 不再有任何期許
On my wedding day I knew my marriage would have no love.
我婚禮那天 我就知道我的婚姻沒有愛情
Yet still I took my vows to God.
但我仍向上帝發了誓
I honoured and obeyed my commitments daily.
每日 我都信守諾言 遵守諾言
You think we are not the same, Thomas, but you're wrong.
你以為我們不同 Thomas 但你錯了
- I'm starving!  - What do you want me to do?
- 我餓死了!  - 你想讓我怎麼辦?
Someone's gotta do something!
總得有人做點什麼!
Listen to me.
聽著
Damn your Templar vows!
讓你聖殿騎士的誓言見鬼去吧!
It was my vows that made me what I am.
是我的誓言告訴我怎樣做人
It was my order that brought me here.
是我的使命帶我來到了這裡
And by God's good grace,
在主的保佑下
it will be the Templars that save your life.
將由聖殿騎士們來拯救你們
Where are you going?
你要去哪?
Why are you leaving?
你為什麼要離開?
Why would he leave?
他為什麼離開?
My Lady, you were with him last.
夫人 您最後跟他在一起
Did he say why he left?
他有說為什麼離開嗎?
You go to your chamber.
回你的房間去
Now.
現在
No.
不
I'll kiss the Bishop's arse if he comes back.
只要他能回來 我什麼都願意做
You're gonna have to kiss a king's arse, Becket, cos they're coming back again.
那你有的事做了 Becket 他們又來了
- It's Thomas!  - Open the gates!
- 是Thomas!  - 打開大門!
Becket, get him! Get him, Becket!
Becket 去接他! 接他 Becket!
- Come on! Quickly! Help him!  - Get the sacks. The sacks!
- 去啊! 快點! 幫幫他!  - 把袋子撿起來 撿袋子!
- Come on!  - Hurry!
- 來啊!  - 快點!
- Run!  - Close the portcullis!
- 快跑!  - 關上閘門!
What was you thinking, Templar?
你想做什麼啊 騎士?
He's stolen the King's food. I've never seen such a thing!
他偷了國王的糧食 我從沒見過這種事!
You are relieved of your command, Captain.
我解除你的任命 隊長
Get back in your rowboat and go home.
回你的小船上去 滾回家吧
- I'm not leaving without my men!  - Oh yes, you are!
- 我不會扔下我的部下離開的!  - 噢 不可能 你必須走!
And I will tell you why. The Pope has had a change of heart.
我來告訴你為什麼 教皇改變心意了
What do you say?
你說什麼?
I say that when your pathetic little army arrives back at your houses,
我說等你那點可憐的軍隊回到家鄉的時候
you will find your lands Christianised.
你會發現你的土地已經皈依基督教了
Your sons enslaved to the Church and your wives serving new husbands.
你們的子女受制於教會 你們的妻子早已令嫁新人
You did not speak to the Pope of my lands?
你沒有和教皇說過讓我的領地獨立?
Why in God's name would I do that?
我到底為什麼要那樣做?
Take this castle, Tiberius!
攻下這座城堡 Tiberius!
And if you do not, you will be sailing home to quite a different world.
如果你沒做到 漂洋過海回家後 將看到一個完全不同的世界
Well, Marshal, you sure know how to pick a bit of shank.
Marshal 你顯然很會挑偷襲的時機
Better than three months of horse meat.
比吃三個月的馬肉好多了
- I'll stick with the pig.  - Then what?
- 我還要豬肉  - 然後呢?
I'll eat you.
我會把你吃了
So, Squire...
護衛...
you can read words?
你認字嗎?
And write them too?
還會寫?
What's your full name?
你的全名是什麼?
Jedediah Coteral.
是Jedediah Coteral
Yeah.
是啊
I've never seen it written before. Huh.
我從未見過它的寫法
It's too quiet. Check the far wall.
太安靜了 去查看下遠牆
To the battlements! Attack!
到城垛了! 有人襲擊!
Cover the west wing. West wing! Come on!
掩護西翼 西翼! 快點!
- Watch out!  - To the right!
- 注意!  - 到右邊去!
Help me!
幫幫我!
The gates! The gates!
大門! 大門!
Where's Marshal?
Marshal在哪?
Fight, Guy! Fight!
上啊 Guy! 上啊!
Baron!
男爵!
Don't move. Be still.
別動 別動
- Hold the keep.  - You can't die.
- 守住要塞  - 你不能死
You can't die. Stay alive! You hear me?
你不能死 活下去! 聽見了嗎?
Hold the keep! Go! Go!
守住要塞! 去啊! 去啊!
Phipps!
Phipps 來啊!
- Come here!  - Hold the gates!
- 來這裡!  - 守住大門!
I've got it. I've got it.
我來了 我來了
Come on, to the gates!
快點 來大門這!
Hold!
守住!
All in! All in!
全部過來! 全部過來!
Stand fast!
別後退!
Shield wall!
組成盾牆!
Shields. Shields up!
防守 舉起盾牌!
Up!
舉起來!
Brace yourselves.
做好準備
Ready! Ready!
準備好了! 準備好了!
- Isabel!  - Get inside!
- Isabel!  - 進去!
Now!
馬上!
- We have to get to the Baron!  - To the keep!
- 我們得去找男爵!  - 去要塞!
- We can't leave him!  - He's gone, all right?
- 我們不能把他丟下!  - 他死了 知道嗎?
Hold the steps! Hold the steps!
守住樓梯! 守住樓梯!
Come on!
快過來!
Marshal!
是Marshal!
Pull him down!
拉他下馬!
- Marshal!  - Come on!
- Marshal!  - 快走啊!
Get it off! Get it off!
快脫下來! 脫下來!
Get back, behind the portcullis!
過來 到鐵閘門後面來!
Come on!
過來啊!
They have prisoners.
他們抓到俘虜了
Boy!
小廝!
Good afternoon, Baron. Did you find my castle to your liking?
下午好啊 男爵 我的城堡還合你的意嗎?
It's the people's castle now.
城堡現在屬於大家了
You said he was gone.
你說他死了的
Those two. Cut off their hands and feet.
這兩個 把他們手腳剁了
- No. - No!
- 不  - 別這樣!
No!
不!
Now, Baron, I want my keep back.
現在 男爵 我要奪回我的要塞
- At my command!  - No!
- 受我統轄!  - 不!
- They'll never surrender.  - Really?
- 他們絕不會投降  - 絕不?
Do it!
剁了!
- Do something!  - We hold the keep.
- 快做點什麼啊!  - 我們得守住要塞
My arse, your stinking castle!
去你媽的狗屁城堡!
God damn you, you murdering whore!
你這該死的 沒人性的臭婊子!
Isn't that the king I am?
我可不就是這樣一個國王嗎?
You betray all that's meant to be king.
你背棄了王者二字的真意
You betray God!
你背叛了上帝!
I betray God?!
我背叛了上帝?!
My crown was passed to me by my brother, and my father before him.
我兄長從我父王手中奪取了王位 之後又傳位於我
I was born to be a king!
我是天生的國王!
It is my birthright! Given to me by God!
我才是真命天子! 天命所授!
You cry for the common man
你為平民吶喊
and in the same breath you curse the crown that protects him!
卻又詛咒著保護他們的王者!
You dare to question my reign...
你竟敢質疑我的王位...
and the lineage of Kings who have reigned before me?!
質疑列位先王時代相傳的王室血統?!
The great amaranthine royalty of Aquitaine...
我偉大 不朽的阿基坦王室
Who forged this land from barbarian horde
是誰將這片土地從野蠻部落
and made it noble and pure!
教化得如此高貴 純淨!
Who gave it order, meaning,
是誰帶來了秩序 意義
and even faith...
甚至信仰...
to thousands of years of loyal subjects!
乃至千百年來的忠誠!
And it is all now questioned by you!
現在你卻來質疑這一切!
And we are forced to sign your precious Magna Carta,
我們被迫簽下你視若珍寶的大憲章
forced by you, a wool merchant!
被你 一個賣羊毛的 逼迫!
I am the blood! I am God's right hand!
我才是王室正宗! 我才是上帝的右手!
And you will never dictate to me how I am to be a king!
你有何德何能來發號施令 教我怎麼當國王!
Now, Baron.
現在 男爵
Which hand did you touch me with?
你當時用哪只手逼我的?
Hold his hand down.
把他的手壓在樁子上
Hold his right hand down!
把他的右手壓在樁子上!
This is not something you should see.
這些不該讓你看到的
Tell your rebels to open the gate, Albany!
讓你的同夥把門打開 Albany!
No surrender!
寧死不屈!
- No surrender!  - Put his other hand up! Do it!
- 寧死不屈!  - 把另一手也綁起來! 動手!
Do it!
快!
We hold, Baron!
我們會守住的 男爵!
We hold!
會守住的!
Put his feet up. Put his feet up!
把他的腳剁了 給我剁了!
Cornhill!
Cornhill啊!
You will yield to your king!
你若不向你的國王屈服!
Or, as God hears me, your head is on a spike!
我向上帝發誓 必將你的頭顱釘在長釘之上!
Now, that monster that they've made, strap his carcass to it.
把他的屍體吊到他們造出來的那怪物上去!
Strap him to it!
吊上去!
Heave!
發射!
There's no one coming, is there?
根本就沒有增援 是嗎?
My scouts report the French have left Calais.
偵察兵來報 法國人已經從加萊起航了
They'll be at our back within days.
數天之後就會抵達我們的後方
Do you know that when I was a child,
你知道嗎 當我還是個孩子時
I once secretly ate every urn of my father's beloved honey peaches.
有一次 我偷偷吃光了我父親最喜歡的水蜜桃
And the next day...
第二天...
he brought before me a servant girl that he had accused of the crime.
他把一個女僕帶到我面前 責罵她吃光了桃子
And he placed her hand on the table, and he drew his knife...
之後 他把她的手按在桌子上 拔出刀...
and he delivered the punishment.
然後就地行刑
And that night, unable to contain my shame,
那天晚上 我羞愧得無以自容
I confessed to him that it was I,
我向父親坦白 那是我所為
his son, who had committed the crime.
是他的兒子做的壞事
Do you know what his response was?
你知道他怎麼回答我的嗎?
He said, "I know.
他說"我知道"
I know.
我是知道的
And that is why I only cut off her finger.
所以我只砍掉了她的手指
You see, John, any action against the throne
聽好了 約翰 任何威脅王座的行為
must be punished ruthlessly.
都必須毫不容情地懲罰
For that is the only way to maintain the absolute power...
這是維護國王絕對君權的...
of a king."
唯一之計"
When they come, you must demand to see the King.
要是他們闖進來 你一定要要求面見約翰王
I want nothing from him.
我和他無話可說
Not even mercy.
更不會請他手下留情
I broke my vow, Isabel.
我已經違背了誓言 Isabel
I have betrayed God's trust.
辜負了主對我的信任
What we did was a sin.
我們的所為是罪孽
Stop hiding... behind vows and commandments.
不要再躲在... 誓言和戒律的背後了
The vows speak of loyalty and abstinence and murder, but...
那些誓言裡只有忠誠 節欲 還有謀殺 但是
why never love, Thomas?
為什麼從不提愛情 Thomas?
The vows of the order...
我許下的誓言...
protect my soul from the blood I've spilt in God's name.
讓我以主之名犯下的殺戮 不會污染我的靈魂
It was the Church that made you do those things.
逼你做這些事的是教會
It was the Templars that gave you a sword
將劍交到你手中的 讓你以主之名舉劍的
and the name of God to wield it.
是聖殿騎士
It was the Templars that made you kill.
讓你去屠殺的是聖殿騎士
Who were you before them?
而在成為聖殿騎士前 你是什麼人?
What was so bad about that man then that makes you resist your desires now?
之前的你有多罪大惡極 讓你現在這樣抗拒自己真心所願?
Thomas...
Thomas啊...
I am not a sin.
我不是罪惡
Sire? Sire?
陛下? 陛下?
Your engineer, sire. The mine is ready.
工程師來報 陛下 坑道準備好了
Will it work?
會有用嗎?
It's right under the keep's foundations.
坑道就在要塞地基的下面
Then take note.
記下來
To my justiciar, send to me 40 pigs.
給最高司法官送信 要他送來40頭豬
The least good for eating.
能吃就行
Deliver that at once.
快馬加鞭地送去
Come on! Hurry up! Move it!
走啊! 快點! 往前走啊!
That's it.
夠了
- Where you going?  - I'm going to plead for terms.
- 你要去哪裡?  - 我要去簽署條款
No!
不行!
- What else is there to do don't you see?  - We hold.
- 你看不出已經沒有其他出路了嗎?  - 只能守住這裡
We hold for what? The French? They're not coming.
我們守著城堡做什麼? 等法國人? 他們根本不會來
- I'll ask for terms. - No!
- 我現在就去簽  - 不行!
We swore an oath. An oath!
我們起過誓了 誓言不可違!
To Albany. To England.
效忠Albany 效忠英格蘭
Your oath is worthless.
你的誓言一錢不值
Magna Carta is worthless.
大憲章也是一錢不值
The Church has annulled it.
教會已經廢止了"大憲章"
Whatever happens here is meaningless.
這裡發生的一切都毫無意義
No. No. Wait!
不 別 等等!
- That's enough, Squire.  - Becket?
- 夠了 護衛  - Becket?
Your boy here tried to take the old man's head off.
你的部下正打算把老傢伙的腦袋擰下來
Becket, leave him be.
Becket 放開他
Now, Guy... get away from him.
Guy... 放開他 馬上
- Now.  - Or what?
- 馬上  - 不然呢?
You'll kill me?
你就殺了我?
- Guy...  - Shut up!
- Guy...  - 閉上嘴!
Baron de Albany gave his life for his beliefs.
de Albany男爵為了自己的信仰獻出了生命
What have you given for yours?
你獻出過什麼?
Coward.
懦夫
There's no salvation to this end.
事情已經無可挽回了
Our souls...
我們都要...
are damned.
萬劫不復了
You are not a coward.
你不是個懦夫
- What are you doing?  - I'm writing my name.
- 你做什麼呢?  - 寫自己的名字
How do you do that?
你怎麼會寫的?
Master Guy taught me.
Guy小師傅教我的
Well, that's you all done then.
嗯 你也就只能做做這個了
What makes a man like you so angry?
你為什麼老是這麼怒氣沖沖的?
I've been angry so long...
我已經這樣很久了...
I don't even remember.
甚至都記不起為什麼了
It's kept you alive though, I suppose.
我猜 你就靠這個活到現在的
I don't think it's gonna get us through this one.
我覺得 這樣不能幫我們熬過這次
- What do you think they're doing?  - Pigs. For a sapper's fire.
- 你覺得他們這是要幹什麼?  - 那些豬 為了在坑道裡點火的
- Sappers?  - They're digging a mine underneath us.
- 坑道?  - 他們在我們下面挖坑呢
Pig's fat, it burns, with the heat of a crucible.
豬的油脂多 用坩堝加熱後 就開始燃燒
Make Way!
讓路!
Go on! Go!
走啊! 快!
Whoa there!
吁 停!
Bring them in.
把它們趕進去
We've got a bigger problem.
我們有更大的麻煩了
Hah! Get in there!
呀! 給我進去!
Go on!
進去!
Coteral.
Coteral啊
It's hot.
很燙手
So what are we gonna do now? Templar.
我們接下去怎麼辦? 聖殿騎士
We get to the other side of the keep.
我們到要塞的另一側
Guy, take the women to the chapel, huh?
Guy 把女人都帶到小禮堂去 嗯?
Go!
去啊!
Hurry, Isabel.
快來 Isabel
Get down! Get down!
趴下! 快趴下!
- I think he's gone.  - I'm not making that mistake again.
- 我看他已經沒命了  - 我可不打算再犯那種錯
Come on.
來啊
OK. One, two.
好 一 二 起
Oh, Maddy. She was beside me.
Maddy呢 她剛才還在我身邊的
Becket. Becket.
Becket. Becket啊.
I'll hold them off.
我拖住他們
How much did they pay to get you out those stocks?
他們花了多少錢從枷鎖下救出了你?
- Five shillings.  - That is cheaper than a whore.
- 五先令  - 比妓女還便宜
Come on, you filthy whores!
來啊 你們這些臭婊子!
If they get through us, you kill the women.
如果我們沒擋住他們 你就把女人都殺了
- No.  - Say it.
- 不  - 答應我
- I can't.  - Say it!
- 我不行  - 答應啊!
I'll kill the women.
我會把女人都殺了
Come on, you whore!
來啊 你們這些婊子!
Forgive me.
原諒我
Thomas. Thomas!
Thomas. Thomas啊!
Thomas!
Thomas啊!
Save her.
救她
No one touch him!
都別碰他!
How's your faith now, Templar?
現在你的信念呢 聖殿騎士?
Why don't you come a little closer...
不如你過來點...
and I'll show you.
我讓你好好看看
You fought bravely.
你作戰很英勇
Is killing a noble thing?
殺戮是件高尚的事嗎?
But a life fought for others is a life worth living.
為他人而戰 才不枉一生
That is a noble thing.
才是高尚的事
A French prince now holds the English crown.
現在一個法國王子登上了英國的王座
Not an easy decision to make.
這是個艱難的決定
Nor was this one.
還有一個決定也是
The Order's over for you, Thomas.
你不再屬於教會了 Thomas
You've earned your freedom as much as any man.
你現在享有和他人一樣的人身自由
Your Grace.
多謝您的恩典
Come on.
走吧
We held.
我們守住了
Within a year, the rebellion was won.
在一年之內 反叛軍取得了勝利
While fleeing for his life, King John died of dysentery.
約翰王在逃亡的路上死於痢疾
What was left of his treasure was never recovered.
而他留下的寶藏從此失去了下落
In time, the great keep of Rochester was rebuilt.
同時 重建了羅徹斯特城堡
It stands to this day.
這座城堡屹立至今
So too does the noble dream that was... Magna Carta.
大憲章... 這個高貴的夢想也同樣如此